It's been five days since the satellite crashed into
Akihabara's Radio Kaikan.
Since morning, many people have gathered here
to see it again,
but the satellite's origin remains unknown,
and there's no timetable
for when it'll be taken down.
Mail Received
Do you have a moment?
Are you here to see the satellite?
Could you tell us where you're from?
Even the billions of heartbeats in the world
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
are nothing to you but insignificant
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Whether we’re trapped in the past or lamenting over the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
predetermination does not allow even the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are but vain privileges allowed to us
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what both clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
So now I cross worldlines every second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And so, a time loop without sadness will once again
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
engulf me, the lone observer
Butterfly
Effect's
Divergence
This is it?
It's delicious!
Miss Amane, you've never had a beef bowl?
No, I've only heard rumors of it.
It's delicious.
It's even better if you put a raw egg on it.
If you call yourself a warrior,
you should be able to come to
a beef bowl place by yourself.
Well, Daru and I come here often.
If you invite us, we'll go with you anytime.
I just remembered!
Last time, I had to pay for Okarin's meal.
It's possible that happened, yes.
It's not just possible! It happened!
Give me back my money!
Sadly, I don't have any on me today.
It's me.
Transfer the funds to my Swiss bank account.
What?
The Organization hacked into
the Geneva servers?
No cell phones.
How terrible...
Um, he's just pretending.
So you were with them too, Suzu?
It was time for my lunch break.
If you came a bit earlier, you could've joined us.
Then, do you want to go all together tomorrow?
I'm sure Okarin would be happy to pay—
What?
The Organization's sabotaging the process,
and it'll take a week to bring the servers back online?
It's Kurisu!
Assistant, did you get any sleep?
Don't call me "assistant."
Hey, part-timer.
If you're done with lunch, get back to work.
What's with her?
A round table?
Indeed.
What's that?
A meeting of lab mems.
Have we ever had one before?
Do you even own a round table?
Not a physical one,
but the true round table lies
within all lab mems' hearts,
right?
Whether it's true or not,
don't put anything weird in my heart.
Do you think there's one in Mayushii's heart too?
Yes, of course.
Really?
Yay!
But what's a round table?
Why a round table?
Are you supposed to be King Arthur?
I'm only a temporary lab mem, anyway.
At any rate...
it's time for a round table.
We need to tell Mayuri about the current situation.
Situation?
And so,
in order to defeat SERN, we must perfect
the PhoneWave (name subject to change)
as soon as possible.
This is too hard for Mayushii to understand!
Just know that SERN is evil.
But how do we perfect it?
We've succeeded in sending
messages to the past, right?
Only twice!
And we don't know what conditions
trigger the phenomenon.
From what we observed last time,
it only occurs when there's electricity.
That's right!
Did you figure something out?
No, "Emails Sent to the Past" is too long.
First, we need to find a name for them.
Another failed attempt to sound cool?
Don't say "another"!
Do you dare mock the great Hououin...
You'll just give it a stupid name, anyway.
How rude!
Then I'll tell you.
I've found the perfect name for the act of sending emails back in time...
I call it "Nostalgia Drive"!
You write it with the kanji for
"journey crossing over time,"
but you read it "Nostalgia Drive."
Too complicated.
Rejected.
Hey, you're the assistant here! You can't reject—
Then let's have a vote.
Who agrees with "Nostalgia Drive"?
Not you too, Mayuri? Daru?
I think Kurisu is right.
Mayushii can't remember a long name like that.
It sounds like something invented by a nerdy teenager.
We should focus on making it easy to understand.
Since it's an email going back in time,
we could call it "Email That Flies Against Time."
What does "flies against time" mean?
That's not easy to understand at all.
It should be "The Email That Leapt Through Time."
That's a bit formal
and hard to say.
You don't get to say that.
Your "Nostalgia Whatsit" was long too!
It's romantic! If it's romantic, it's okay!
So we can shorten it to Time-Leap.
Then we don't know what leapt through time!
Is it an email? A girl? Maybe a banana?
Mayushii has an idea!
Um... "Back to the mail"!
That would be going back to the email,
not back in time,
which doesn't make sense.
Then "DeLorean Mail"!
That makes even less sense!
Hey...
Why don't we just shorten it to "D-Mail"?
I like that.
Okay, it's decided then.
We will now begin the experiments
with D-Mail (name subject to change).
We can also cut the "(name subject to change)."
The operation is called "Operation Urd."
We don't need that either.
But we don't know what it takes to send a D-Mail
or what it's got to do with electricity.
That's what we're going to find out.
I, Hououin Kyouma, have an idea.
We forgot the simplest and
most important condition...
which is the time it occurred!
The first D-Mail was sent between 12:00 and 13:00.
The second occurred around 18:00.
If we attempt to replicate it at those times,
we'll succeed.
Probably.
That sounds too easy.
It's worth a shot.
Mayuri, the banana!
Mayushii's running low on bananas.
Do we have to put the banana in?
"Put the banana in"!
Daru, not now.
I want to see if it turns into jelly.
Now, assistant,
put the banana inside.
"Put the banana inside..."
Enough, you pervert!
I'm sorry.
I'll buy you a new banana later.
Really?
I'm so happy!
Okarin and Daru never buy me any.
Geez, you two...
Ow!
Being clumsy isn't cute.
The heck?
Pain, pain, go away!
Thanks, Mayuri.
Stop making a Lesbomagnetic Field and prepare the D-Mail.
Right.
Is 120 seconds okay for the time?
Indeed.
Begin Operation Urd!
Now!
It's here.
It's here!
Where's the banana?
It's a gel-bana!
I've solved it at last.
As I thought,
time was the D-Mail's missing factor!
Nice job, Okabe.
I didn't realize it was so simple.
Does it bother you?
Still, I respect you for having the guts to admire me so closely.
Anyway, did the D-Mail arrive?
It did.
It says it was sent five days ago.
Did you send two messages, Miss Makise?
No, just one.
It was split into two messages.
By the way, what does this message mean?
Look it up yourself.
Come to think of it,
the last D-Mail was also split
into multiple messages,
and some of it was lost.
And it went back in time five days too.
Yeah, there must be some kinds of rules for it.
Which means that D-Mail...
...was calling me an empty-headed idiot?
Took you a while.
Curse you, Christina. Taking advantage of a...
Wait a minute. Why are you buying so much?
The only food we need is
nonperishable cup ramen.
One bag of the cheap chocolate is plenty.
I'm celebrating our experiment's success.
Go put it back.
Cheap-ass.
That's right.
I was so happy about the
experiment's success that I forgot.
We learned SERN's terrifying secret.
And I even got Mayuri involved.
Was this really for the best?
It's Shining Finger.
What?
What are you doing?
You don't have your cell phone?
The great Hououin Kyouma's cell phone is
currently being used for an experiment that'll be remembered throughout history.
It's not here.
O-O-Okarin!
Who's that sweet-ass...
I mean sexy... 3D girl?
I'll introduce you.
This is Shining Finger, Kiryu Moeka.
H-Hi, Kiryu—
Even I once had hope for the 3D world.
Yo!
Are you guys doing something fun?
Indeed.
We're performing an experiment
that'll become legendary—
Legendary is fine...
but the boss is really pissed off.
He says the vibrations from
the second story are really bad.
"I'll raise your rent 10,000 yen!"
he was saying.
10,000 yen?
Okay, leave this to me.
Tell my assistant to stop the
experiments for the moment, Daru.
Roger.
You're shining like never before...
Is Makise Kurisu still there?
Oh, yeah. You were staring
at her back there, weren't you?
So, what happened earlier?
What's your deal with her?
Did something happen in the past?
Nothing in the past, no.
Yes, it was the summer we were eight.
And on the dry riverbed of the Mississippi,
your red-eared slider ran away...
It was nothing!
I saw her for the first time earlier!
Anyway, you should go see the boss.
What are you doing upstairs?
It's been shaking like an earthquake.
We're performing an experiment
that'll rewrite scientific history,
but don't worry.
We won't do any more today...
I said stop!
What are you doing?
Miss Makise said to let her
do it just one more time.
I sent you a message. Did you see it?
Of course not!
I warned you five days ago...
Don't be stupid—
Oh, when we weren't doing the experiments,
your phone went off a bunch of times.
Really!
Sorry!
Are you maybe...
How've you been?
?
Well?
Sorry!
Are you maybe...
How've you been?
?
Well?
Hey
How've you been? Okabe
Well?
Find out anything about the IBN 5100 ?
Why didn't she just ask me?!
What's wrong?
I don't know,
but he probably isn't getting enough calcium.
Whose fault is that?
Well, I got plenty of data,
and I pretty much figured out the rules
for how the D-Mail works.
What?
Send a modified command to the
microwave's heading function (reverse spin)
Open the microwave door while heating
(Timing -> Unconfirmed)
Each second on the timer
represents one hour back in time.
Electricity
While the electricity is sparking,
send message to the phone
Prerequisites to making the electricity appear?
(time between 12:00 PM and 18:00 PM?)
Number of characters that can be sent
with a D-Mail -> (12 half-width, 6 full-width) x3
You can control the time the PhoneWave
(name subject to change) sends a message back.
One second on the timer = One hour in reality
One hundred twenty seconds turns into 5 days.
At the same time, anything placed into the
PhoneWave becomes jelly
(teleportation confirmed, as well)
It's amazing that she figured out how to
control how far it goes back, isn't it?
But the maximum amount of information that can
be sent back is 36 English characters
or 18 Japanese characters.
It's too small.
I'd like to fix that.
I'm sure you can't send anything too big
or send too much.
Maybe it's that Curb black hole...
Kerr black hole, indeed.
The hole's too tight!
Can you repeat that, Mayushii?
The part about the hole?
Shut up, pervert!
Anyhow, we can work out the details later,
but I'll say this:
August 2, 2010,
is a day that mankind will remember forever,
for the Future Gadget Laboratory
has succeeded in developing humanity's
first time machine!
It's not the first one, right?
SERN beat us.
We didn't "develop" it, anyway.
It was all coincidence.
All of you, disrespecting my great declaration...
But Okarin...
I'm glad your experiments worked.
Where am I?
You're not moving.
Time and space have switched places here.
The event horizon?
You can't move through space,
and time is extended forever.
One second of your time
is an eternity to me.
Is the edge of the universe running away?
No, that's not it, but something's expanding.
What is?
The universe?
Me?
You mustn't look back.
Eternity isn't infinite.
Even if time appears to extend toward eternity,
an end still exists.
When will it be one second later?
Look forward.
Reach the end.
You mustn't turn back.
That emailing freak again?
Her persistence...
You there?
It's dark
Wake up
I'm here
You asleep?
Am I bugging you?
Sorry for yesterday
Moeka
"Sorry for yesterday."
"Can I come see you?"
I'm here
At least answer me. Or are you pretending
to not be there?
Moeka
It didn't occur to you that I was asleep?
Wake up
Were you asleep?
Moeka
I was!
It's dark
I'm coming up the stairs right now.
Moeka
What?
I'm outside.
I'll knock. If you're there, respond.
Moeka
You said I could come see,
right?
Moeka
Why use your cell phone?
I'm right here.
I'm not looking at it. Just say it.
I can show you, but I didn't think you'd come this early.
I get it!
You really want to interview me, don't you?
Why don't you talk?
I see... So that's it.
You're terrified of Mad Scientist
Hououin Kyouma's sinister aura!
It's easier to send emails...
Well then, show me the IBN 5100.
Very well.
But I'm just showing it to you.
Once you've seen it, leave!
Is that all right?
Is she just a retro-PC fan?
Let me take a picture
Moeka
But not my face.
If you photograph my face,
I'll have to silence you forever...
Please!
I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?
I'd be happy if you'd help me
carry it.
Moeka
"I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?"
"I'd be happy if you'd help me carry..."
Why am I suddenly lending it to you?
And if you really want me to loan it to you,
then look at me and say it.
Will you loan it to me?
Sadly, no.
I'm only borrowing it myself.
When I'm done,
I have to return it to its original owner.
Its original owner?
Yanabayashi Shrine.
Guten Morgen.
You're Miss Kiryu from yesterday, right?
I didn't introduce you yesterday, did I?
My favorite right arm, Supah Hakah Daru.
It's "Super Hacker," man. Seriously.
Anyway, I thought I'd improve
the PhoneWave a little.
It's currently a bit of a pain in the ass, right?
Sending the D-Mails to the past, that is.
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
I-It's nothing.
You misheard.
He didn't say, "Sending emails to the past."
He said, "Sen Dingma Ils Tot Hepast,"
which is ancient Sumerian for
"Did you eat breakfast?"
Good morning, Okarin!
Can Mayushii use the time machine before you
to prepare the chicken?
Okabe, I had an idea about the time machine.
It's me.
This is bad.
No.
Information about #8
has been leaked to a third party.
Ah, I get it. I'll do something about it.
What's going on?
Depending on the situation I'll have to seal their mouth to keep them in check.
He's totally ignoring all three of us?
We can't let the Organization find out...
Don't email me while I'm on the phone!
Could that be...
It can't be
It can't be FB?
"FB"?
Very well. I'll tell you everything.
Since you've found out,
there's nothing else I can do.
Kiryu Moeka,
from now on, you're Lab Mem 005!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
With my field of view restricted
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
I cannot escape the merciless control of the twelve
ansoku no asu wo negatta
While wishing for a tomorrow of repose
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
I headed for the sacred event horizon in my hand
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
Pledges are imprisoned, and false evidences are showing their outline
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
This world of life blindly lets the time pass by
habatake butterfly
Spread your wings
kiseki no butterfly
butterfly of miracles
anata he sasagu
I dedicate it to you
namida no butterfly
Oh butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
butterfly of radiance
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
everything will now be rewritten